Delaney, James Joseph; Papers apap241
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Communications, 1956-1978; 2; 2 cubic ft.
  - Aircraft Crimes, Army Band to St. Patrick’s Day, Maspseth Library Release, 1972 March (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 62)
  - Byelorussian Independence, Illegal Aliens, Northern Ireland, Science Winner Dora Lee, Northern Ireland, Statement, 1972 March (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 63)
  - Civil Service Retirees, Irish Contribution, Statement, 1972 April (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 64)
  - Cooleys Anemia, Aid to Handicapped, Urging Freedom for Simas Kudirka, Release, 1972 April (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 65)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, Eulogy, 1972 May (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 66)
  - Wyckoff Heights Hospital Remarks, Queens County VA Hospital, Boulevard Gardens, Disabled American Veterans, Statement, 1972 May (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 67)
  - Separating Social Security from Welfare and Including 20% Boost in Cash Payments, Revenue Sharing, Urging Hearings on DES, Release, 1972 May (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 68)
  - Revenue Sharing, DES Ban, Delaney Wins Another Round in the Fight for a Clean Environment, Fair Campaign Practices, Control of Toxic Chemicals, Release, 1972 June (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 69)
  - Congressman Philbin, Philip, Eulogy, 1972 June (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 70)
  - Farley, Jim Insertion, 1972 June (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 71)
  - Revenue Sharing, Ridgewood Property Owners Association, Statement, 1972 June (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 72)
  - Cyclamate Compensation Bill, Release, 1972 July (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 73)
  - AEHEPA: A Tradition of Service, Opposing H.R. 1336 Cyclamate Compensation Bill, DES, Statement, 1972 July (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 74)
  - Passage of Cooley’s anemia Bill, Release, 1972 August (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 75)
  - DES Ban, Statement, 1972 August (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 76)
  - Farley, Jim Insertion, 1972 August (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 77)
  - HEW’s Non Discrimination in Employment, Release, 1972 September (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 78)
  - H.R16555 Tuition Tax Credit, Cyclamates, Statement, 1972 September (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 79)
  - Gateway Bill, Senator Nelson’s Food Additives Hearing, Irish Americans in Texas, Statement, 1972 September (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 80)
  - FDA’s Push for Delegation of Amendment, Bill to Assure Social Security Increase, Israeli Assassination at Olympics, Irish Americans held in Texas, Disaster Relief to Non Public Schools, Release, 1972 September (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 81)
  - Congressman Ryan, Eulogy, 1972 September (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 82)
  - Congressman Colmer, Halpern, Garmatz, Cellear, Extension of Remarks, 1972 October (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 83)
  - Tuition Tax Credit, Release, 1972 October (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 84)
  - 33rd Regular Democratic Club, Congressional Briefing by Henry Kissinger, Ukrainian Independence, Jim Farley’s Insertion, Statement, 1973 January (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 85)
  - Pension Exemption, Educational Diversity, Newsletter, Release, 1973 January (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 86)
  - Lithuanian Independence, Catholic Bishop Pastoral and Cardinal Krol on Abortion, Eulogy for President Johnson, Installation Night at the Ridgewood Club, Statement, 1973 February (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 87)
  - Ban on Saccharin, Return of Irish Americans from Texas, Abortion, Release, 1973 February (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 88)
  - Delaney’s Views on National Issues, 1973 February (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 89)
  - Correspondence, Canal Zone Letter to the President, 1973 March (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 90)
  - Home with Honor Day (Re: GI’s Back From Vietnam), Conservative Party Dinner, National Fire Research Safety and Training Center, March 1973 with Photograph, Hearings before the Judiciary Committee on Irish Americans in Texas Statement and Release, 1973 March (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 91)
  - Total DES Ban, Statement and Release, 1973 April (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 92)
  - Honorable Allen, Leo E., Eulogy, 1973 April (Box 14 (2-Communications), Folder 93)
  - H.R. 6458 to Provide for Operation of PHS Hospital, Statement, 1973 May (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Attorney General Richardson (Fort Worth 5), 1973 June (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 2)
  - H.R. 3549 before Subcommittee on Compensation and Pension, Statement, 1973 June (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 3)
  - Lithuania Anniversary, Farley Fine at 85, Tribute to John J. Rooney, Jim Farley’s 85th Birthday Extension of Remarks, 1973 June (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 4)
  - Crackdown on Asbestos, Condemns New FDA Proposal on Residues Release, 1973 July (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 5)
  - H.R. 5590 before the Subcommittee on Science Research and Development, VA Tour of St. Albans Naval Hospital Speech, Statement, 1973 July (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 6)
  - Jim Farley Golf Classic-Success Story, Statement, 1973 October (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 7)
  - Delaney Fights Postal Relocation, Release, 1973 October (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 8)
  - Day Lights Savings Time (Delaney Introduces), Delaney Fights against Social Security Earnings Limit, Release, 1973 November (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 9)
  - Delaney Opposes NIH Guidelines on Research on Living Human Fetus, Statement, 1973 December (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 10)
  - Correspondence. EPA Head Russell Train to Delay on Coal Decision Affecting Con Edison in NY, 1973 December (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 11)
  - Independence of Ukraine, Statement, 1974 January (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 12)
  - Correspondence. Includes Federal Energy Office Mass Transportation in NY During the Energy Crisis, NYC Rent Increase Exemption for Seniors Receiving SSI, 1974 February (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 13)
  - Dr. Porreth, Samuel Appointment, Mr. Delaney, Carey and Smith, Release, 1974 February (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 14)
  - U.N. adds 2 New Languages, Statement, 1974 April (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 15)
  - James A. Farley, Lithuanian Independence, Retirement of John J. Rooney, Statement, 1974 June (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 16)
  - Newsletter “Congressman Delaney Reports”, Statement, 1974 July (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 17)
  - Subcommittee on Compensation and Pension on H.R. 3549, Statement, 1974 August (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 18)
  - Nomination of Nelson Rockefeller, Mass Transit Bill, Latvian Independence, Statement, 1974 November (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 19)
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Hugh Carey. Statement, 1974 December (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 20)
  - “Ford” State of the Union, Ukrainian Independence, Statement, 1975 January (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 21)
  - Lester Wolff and Northern Ireland, Lithuanian Independence, Statement, 1975 February (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 22)
  - Hungarians in Romania, Statement, 1975 May (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 23)
  - Farley, Jim, Statement, 1975 June (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 24)
  - Captive Nations Week, Baltic Freedom (Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe), Statement, 1975 July (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 25)
  - Fluoridation and Cancer, Statement and Release, 1975 July (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 26)
  - Fluoridation and Drinking Water, Release, 1975 July-1975 August (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 27)
  - Education Bills, DES (Senate Passage of Ban), Eulogy for Andrew J. Viglietta, Includes New York State Right to Life Convention Letter/Convention, The Steu ben Society, Release and Statement, 1975 September (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 28)
  - Our Heritage that is Greece, Hon. James A. Farley, Mrs. Esther Savitzky (Announcement of Death of Mr. of Congresswoman Bella Abzug), John J. Rooney, M.C. (Eulogy), A Courageous People, Statement, 1975 October (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 29)
  - EPA Fluorocarbons and Ozone, Statement, 1975 October-1976 November (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 30)
  - NCI Fluoridation Study Letters. Includes Latvian Independence, Clergy speak out against the Human Impact of NY Default (Cooke/Mugavero Statement), John J. Rooney, M.C. (Special Order Memorial Tribute), Albanian Independence, 1975 November (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 31)
  - Delaney battles for Queens’ seniors (Title IX, Older American Act SCSEP), A Crisis of the American Spirit (Rule on NYC Bill-H. Res. 865 on H.R. 10481, Release, 1975 December (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 32)
  - Two Elected Statesman with Young Ideas, Cancer in Our Drinking Water, Staats-Zeitung und Herold, Support for Soviet Jewry, Human Rights Day, National Conference on Soviet Jewry, CBS Editorial, NYC Presented by Peter Kohler, Editorial Director, Finnish Sisu and Paying Debts, Statement, 1975 December (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 33)
  - Ukrainian Independence-May it become a reality, Delaney salutes Lenoid Plyusch (Ukrainian intellectual free after two and a half years in Soviet prison- 94 H. Con. Res 41), Delaney Letter Spearheads Major Attack on Illegal Narcotics, City Awards 6.2. Million Federal Grant (Senior Citizen), Release, 1976 January (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 34)
  - Background Information for Brochure of Greater NY Conference on Soviet Jewry, 1976 January (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 35)
  - Foreword to James Flynn, Winning the Presidency: The Difficulty of Election, 1976 January (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 36)
  - January Newsletter to Senior Citizens: Tax information for seniors (Not used in 1976 but saved for future reference), 1976 January (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 37)
  - Estonian Independence, Delaney hails action to ban Red-2, SST Landings at Kennedy Airport (Delegation telegrams from Rep. Delaney to Governor Carey WM. Ronan, Release, 1976 February (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 38)
  - Letter Statement honoring Judge Abraham J. Multer, Lithuanian Independence, A Polish American Patriot (Birthday of Gen. Thaddeus Kosciusko, Outline-Installation Night at Amerind Democratic Club of Elmhurst, Right to Life Constitutional Amendment (Abortion), Statement, 1976 February (Box 15 (2-Communications), Folder 39)
  - Senate Statement on Tax Deduction Bill, Westinghouse Science Scholarship Winner George Yancopoulous of Elmhurst, Release, 1976 March (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 1)
  - Yearbook letter to class of 1976, Horace Greeley Jr. High School, 1976 March (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 2)
  - Statement. Includes Czechoslovakian Freedom Fighter (Thomas G. Masaryic: Birthday), Hungarian Independence, National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control Site Selection Board, 1976 March (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 3)
  - Community Planning Board 1, In support of Engine Company 260 in Ravenswood, In memory of Hon. Wright Patman, State of NY Temporary Planning Commission for Establishment of a Public Medical School, Statement, 1976 March (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 4)
  - Clippings. Includes Wire in support of Howard L. Hurwitz, suspended principle of LIC High School, 1976 March (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 5)
  - Background Information on Stanley N. Lundine- 39th CD (Jamestown NY), 1976 March (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 6)
  - District Leader Endorsements, 1976 April (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 7)
  - Mr. Lincoln would be Proud (Of the People Article- Dorsey’s Short, Ridgewood Times), Warsaw Ghetto Uprising Statement, 1976 April (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 8)
  - Background Information for Queens Jewish Community Council, 1976 April (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 9)
  - Delaney’s Involvement with Port Authority SST Ban, Release, 1976 April (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 10)
  - “Mr. Democrat” (James A. Farley), Before the House Committee on Affairs (Re: Extension of Veterans Education), Boy Scouts of America- Eagle Court of Honor Troop 383 (St. Pancras) - Glendale (George Wolff, Armenian Independence, Statement, 1976 May (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 11)
  - “Special Bicentennial Salute to the German-American Community” (Staats-Zeitung Und Herold: July 4, 1976 Weekend Edition, Israeli Independence Day, A Polish Anniversary” (Commemoration of the Polish Constitution of 1791), Release, 1976 May (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 12)
  - Queen Trim Committee Bulletin, 1976 June (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 13)
  - Polish Commemoration (Pozan Polish Workers Uprising), Berlin Anniversary (1953 Workers’ Uprising in East Berlin), Baltic Freedom Day, Statement, 1976 June (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 14)
  - Captive Nations Week, Statement, 1976 July (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Action on Behalf of the Senior Citizens, 1977 August (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 16)
  - What’s Right with NY- Philip Morris, Expansion on Park Avenue, Statement, 1976 August (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 17)
  - Appointment of Shirley Chisholm to House Majority Leadership position, Newsletter for Republican Campaign, Release, 1976 August (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Condolence for Dorsey Short (Editor of the Ridgewood Times), 1976 September (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 19)
  - Clippings, Phillip Ross v. NY Congressional Delegation, Bill to Bar Interstate OTB Looses Ground, 1976 September (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 20)
  - A German Patriot (Baron Von Steuben/Steuben Society, Release, 1976 September (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 21)
  - Includes Special Order Honoring Departing Congresswoman Bella Abzul and Congressman Wilbur Mills, Statement, 1976 October (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 22)
  - Statements, 1976 October (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 23)
  - House Leadership Meeting with Carter. Includes photograph, 1976 November (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 24)
  - Delaney Demands Immediate Action on Burn Units, Latvian Independence Day, Release, 1976 November (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 25)
  - Clippings. Includes Hellenic Times and The Urban Tree Act, 1976 November (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, The Greater NY Conference on Soviet Jewry, 1977 January (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 27)
  - NY Bible plays Important Role at Inaugural, Independence of Ukraine, Statement, 1977 January (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 28)
  - Declaration of Independence of the Republic of Estonia, Lithuanian National Day (Lithuanian Independence) Polish American Commemoration (Gen. Thaddeus Kosciusko), Statement, 1977 February (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 29)
  - New Approach to Tax Incentives, Independence Day of the Byelorussian Republic, Eulogy for John A. Coleman of NY Stock Exchange, Hungarian Uprising, Statement, 1977 March (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 30)
  - Taras Shevchenko: Symbol of freedom, In praise of Greece (Greek Independence Day), Bulgarian Independence, Release, 1977 March (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 31)
  - Story to Bruce Drake, NY Daily News Re: Queens Civic Courthouse, 1977 March (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 32)
  - Delaney Amendment, Release, 1977 May (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, Korea Survey WCBS-TV, 1977 June (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 34)
  - Disclaimer of Co Sponsorship of 95th H.R. 7638 Comprehensive Health Care Insurance Act, Urban Tree Act/ Ridgewood Tree Program, Statement, 1977 June (Box 16 (2-Communications), Folder 35)
  - White House Agency Reorganization Questionnaire, 1977 July (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 1)
  - Opening statement as Rules Committee Chairman on the National Energy Act 95th, H.R. 8444, Comments on TV Coverage of House for Select Committee on Congressional Operation, Most Favored Nation Status for Rumania, Disability Insurance for the Blind, Statement, 1977 July (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 2)
  - Anything They Can Do We Can Do Better – Delaney pushes East Coast Cinema, Release, 1977 August (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 3)
  - Reception Honoring Koch, Ed, Statement, 1977 September (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence. Includes Honorary Sponsorship of NY Committee to Free Anatoly Shcharnsky (Soviet Jew), EDA Grant for Tree Removal, Greetings to Women’s American Ort Inc. 50th Anniversary, 1977 September (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 5)
  - Non Recognition of Vietnam, 1977 September (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 6)
  - Delaney Bill to Allow Hair Dye Ban, Heading Paste Up,Release, 1978 January (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 7)
  - Tuition Tax Relief: Written Statement Submitted to Senate Finance Committee, Tuition Tax Relief: Oral Testimony before the Senate Finance Committee, Statement, 1978 January (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 8)
  - Tuition Relief, a Hero of Two Worlds- Birthday of Thaddeus Kosciusko, Statement, 1978 February (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 9)
  - Delaney gets FDA Support for Hair Dye Bill, Delaney Renews Push for Hair Dye Ban Bill, Release, 1978 February (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 10)
  - “Middle Income Student Assistance Act 1978”,Statement, Delaney and Others, 1978 March (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 11)
  - Textile Imports-Congressional Record, Fiscal 1979 Funding for Arthritis Research, Statement, 1978 April (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 12)
  - Ridgewood Times, Release, 1978 April (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 13)
  - Cancer Causing Chemicals, Release, 1978 July (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 14)
  - Statements, 1978 August (Box 17 (2-Communications), Folder 15)